

## **ANU A KALAM**

# **Summary**

An IT professional with passion for tailored solutions seeks the position of Software Engineer in a thriving, exciting, and growing company. Comes with Master's degree in Computer Science and two years experience with HTML, JavaScript, CSS, PHP, and fundamentals of React JS, to provide quality support to company's IT team in developing and deploying web-based event and registration software tool.

### **Contact**

#### Phone:

+971 569447553 +971 588359944

#### Email:

anukalaam@gmail.com

# Languages

English Hindi Malayalam

# **Skill Highlights**

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused

## **Experience**

IT Support- 02/2018 to 07/2021 Safety Marine Services LLC, Sharjah

**Software Developer** – 3/2017 to 01/2018 **CEE MART Solutions**, **Sharjah** 

Web Developer - 11/2015 to 11/2016 Imark Technologies, Cochin

Programming Instructor - 10/2010 to 06/2011 University Institute of Technology, Alleppey

## **Professional Skills**

**Programming I Scripting Languages:** 

PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJs Fundamentals, Basic Knowledge in Java & ASP.NET, C, C++, MySQL,

Frame Works:

Laravel, Codeignator

CMS:

Wordpress

## **Education**

Course	Institution	% of Marks	Year of Passing
MSc Computer Science	University Institute of Technology, Alappuzha	73	2012
BSc Computer Science	University Institute of Technology, Alappuzha	80	2009
Plus Two (HSE)	Bishop Hodges HSS, Mavelikkara	87	2006
SSLC	Bethany Balikamadam HSS, Nangiarkulangara	92	2004

## **Projects**

### **Socialwifi**

Socialwifi is a technology that allows a business to turn their free Wifi into a social marketing device connecting them to their customers on auto pilot. Social WiFi opens the channels to leveraging the growing social media networks. Due to increased customer engagement, ease of use for the customer and the collection of useful customer's data, business should also see an increase in sales. Finally, collecting customers' emails and having these automatically added to mailing list means we've opened up an ongoing communication channel with our customers.

Technologies used: Laravel , JQuery, Ajax, MySQL

#### Responsibilities:

- Design and coding of User panel and admin panel.
- Testing of all module.
- Create API for mobile Apps.
- Support and maintenance.

### Propertize.in

Propertize.in is an online platform that features property for rent and sale. This platform will manage multiple levels of users from property owners, brokers, property managers and service providers.

Technologies used: Core PHP, Javascript, JQuery, Ajax, MySQL

#### Responsibilities:

- Developing user panel and admin panel.
- Testing of all module.
- Create API for mobile Apps.
- Support and maintenance for the website and mobile apps.

### **Property Console**

Property Console is an online Property Management Software. Users can access and update their property management data. The users of this system are Property Managers. Property Console has a fully secure, accredited trust accounting module. It keeps track of rental property income & expenses. It has an automate rent reminders and receipts to user's tenants.

Technologies used: : Core PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, AngularJS, MySQL

#### Responsibilities

- Developing Agent Panel, Landlord Panel and Admin panel
- Designing database structure
- Testing of all modules

### Personal Details :-

Father's Name : Abdul Kalam

Nationality : Indian

Husband' Name : Nissamuddeen.N

**Date of Birth** : 18.12.1988

**Gender** : Female

Marital Status : Married

Passport No : M2882973

Visa Status : Resident Visa

I hereby declare that the above furnished information are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and believe.

Anu A Kalam